不要啊
Yelling No.
不要 不 不 不
No. No. No. No.
这样看上去精神病院像消失了一样
It's as if the asylum had vanished.
但不幸必然还在那些高墙后面上演
The misery that must behind those walls.
精神上的恐惧是无从逃离的
There's no escape from the terrors of the mind.
没错
Indeed.
又了结了一起案子
Well another case concluded.
我本不必离开贝克街的
[unintelligible]
这样的案子连一个善于观察的孩子都能解决
An observant child could have solved it.
祝你的研讨会顺利  谢谢你
Good Luck with the seminar and thank you.
这是个殊荣 亲爱的朋友
It's a privilege my dear fellow
毕竟我们成功地破了案
if it's a successful case after all.
福尔摩斯
And Holmes,
别感到无聊哦
don't be bored.
Glovin城堡
Glovin castle.
Glovin
Glovin.
它太美了 Robert
It's so beautiful Robert.
我从没想过它有这么美
I never expected it to be so beautiful
它真的一直都是你们家的吗?
and it's really always belonged to your family?
大概有四五百年了吧
For about 4 or 5 hundred years or so.
我想进去看看
I want to see it.
不行 Hettie
No Hettie.
怎么不行?
Why can't I see it?
亲爱的 你不明白
My darling girl you don't understand,
我不可以这么随便地去拜访Glovin
I can't just drop in at Glovin.
你也不行
Neither can you.
就算你极可爱又极富有 你还是不可以去那里
You maybe utterly divine and impossibly rich but you can't.
可是为什么我不可以呢?
But why can't I?
这城堡是你的啊
You own it,
你是St.Simon勋爵 那是你的房子
you're Lord St. Simon, it's your house.
那是一处祖屋 算在我的名下而已
It's an ancestral home, which is mine.
可是真正住在那里的是些仆人
You see it's the servants who really live there.
事实上他们每个人在Glovin住的时间都比我长
Actually every one of them has spent more of their life in Glovin than I have.
而我不想把他们赶出去
And I won't have them put out.
我明白了
I see,
那么就算我们结婚了
so even when we're married
如果我想到那儿去
if I want to visit
也得提前禀报?
I have to send on ahead?
是的 提早一两天更好
Yes, preferably a day or two ahead.
噢 我真是没想到 一副皇家作派
Oh, I didn't realize, like royalty.
是的
Yes.
没问题吗 Robert?
Will it be all right Robert?
你说什么呢 亲爱的?
What my darling?
我的身份
That I mind about me at what I am
还有我的出身
and where I come from,
我是说你的家族和仆人们介意吗?
the servants I mean and your family?
他们已经把你视为一位有异国风情的女子了
They already think of you as being one of the exotic.
可我是个矿主的女儿 来自矿区
But I'm a miner's daughter from a mining camp.
尽管我爸爸从那里挖出了金子
Pa might have been digging gold out there
可我依然是个矿主的女儿
but it still makes me a miner's daughter.
不要紧的
Doesn't matter.
这样的教育对于乡村生活来说堪称完美
Perfect education for the country life,
整个郡都臣服在你脚下
you'll have the whole county at your feet,
我也是你的
as you have me.
噢 天哪 你看
Oh my, will you look at that.
它在那儿干嘛?
What's it doing here?
在Glovin一直有个类似动物园的地方
There's always been some sort of zoo at Glovin.
我的下人一直打理着它
My latter fellow's interest to keep it going.
我一直有个奇特的想法
You know I have a fancy
觉得这美洲豹就像是你
that cat's from the Americas like you.
它到这儿欢迎我们了
Actually he's come to welcome here.
你这个狂野又美丽的家伙
You wild and beautiful thing.
它的狂野美丽可不及你的一半
Not half as wild and beautiful as you.
水
Water.
洒落尘土的水
Water into dust.
来吧
Come on.
Amelia 让她把狗给我吧
Amelia why don't you let her give the dog to me?
不行 这狗得跟我呆在一起
No, no, she stays with me.
它也许会被马踩到的
She might get under the horses.
我们能到这里简直是奇迹
It's a wonder we got here at all.
衣服到了 他们也到了
Its arrived and so have they.
你说了多少?
How much did you say?
你说什么?
What did you say?
他们曾把孩子送到巴黎去
They sent the child to Paris.
去干嘛?
What for?
去上学
To school.
没错 美国人是会把他们的女儿送到巴黎去
Yes Americans do send their daughters to Paris,
- 我是我的印象... - 我表示怀疑
that's what I was given to understand.
就我看来 巴黎的空气里 要么洋溢着轻浮 要么充满哲理
You know in my experience Paris breaths either triviality or philosophy.
都对你过日子没有什么用处
Neither helpful companion in life.
嗯 没错
No I suppose not.
呃 至少这孩子不是个演员
Well at least the child is not an actress.
噢 Florence
Oh Florence
噢 Alice Alice Alice
Alice Alice Alice
Hettie 她们可是你未来的家人
Now, now Hettie, they're your future family.
她们都想喜欢上你
They want to like you.
她们想喜欢Robert勋爵未来的新娘
They want to like Lord Robert's future bride.
别再这么傻了 Hettie
Stop being so silly Hettie.
可是 Alice 难道你没瞧见那些妇人?
Oh Alice, but Alice have you seen those women?
好了 Hettie Doran
Now Hettie Doran
让我帮你回忆一下
I'd like to remind you of a certain incident
一年多以前 在Tompkins Gulch 发生的那件事吧
which occurred in Tompkins Gulch not 2 years ago.
那头熊!
The bear.
Alice 我当时吓死了
Alice I was scared to death.
噢 你吓退了那头熊
Awe, you faced that bear down you did.
我告诉你 我当时连动都动不了
I couldn't move I tell you.
可是你瞪着它 把它吓退了
You faced him down.
当时你相信自己 于是就做到了
You believed in yourself and you did it.
现在下楼去吧
Now you get down those stairs.
我亲爱的Henrietta
My dear Henrietta
你不能住在Glovin
you cannot live at Glovin.
为什么?
Why not?
因为Glovin不适合居住
Because Glovin isn't fit for habitation.
可是它真的很完美
But it's just perfect.
我们很快就能把它修缮一新
We'll soon get it round.
它是我所见到过的最美的地方了
I say it's the most beautiful place I've ever seen.
你难道不记得那些可爱的景象了吗?
Don't you remember how lovely it was
男人们带着镰刀
when all the men came with their scythes
到庄园上割草
to mow the hay in the park
还有那些夏夜的聚会?
and the summer parties?
房子里里外外的每一盏灯
Every lamp in the house was lit
都点亮了
and outside
还有月光下干草的味道
the smell of the hay in the moonlight,
你还记得吧?
you remember?
当然 当然
Yes, yes.
我都还记得呢
I remember.
亲爱的歇洛克 福尔摩斯先生
Dear Mr. Sherlock Holmes,
我父亲离家出走了 您能帮我找到他吗?
my father has run away. Please will you help me find him?
Timothy
Timothy.
我的猫Boswald失踪了
My cat Boswald is missing.
钱不是问题
Money no object.
我来告诉你我是怎么想的
Well I'll tell you what I actually think.
我觉得她漂亮极了
I think she's extraordinarily pretty
我就是这样想的
that's what I think.
而且我觉得Robert爱得神魂颠倒
And I think Robert is head over heels in love.
没错
I agree.
我就是这么想的
That's what I think.
Bella也是这么想的 对吧 我的天使?
And Bella thinks so too don't you my angel?
Bella说Doran小姐也是个泼辣的女孩
Bella says Miss.Doran is very [unintelligible].
泼辣
Very [unintelligible].
亲爱的Henrietta
Dear Henrietta
你可别把Amelia的话太过当真了
you mustn't take what Amelia says too seriously.
我一个字儿也没听见
I didn't hear a word of all that.
Robert就应该有你这样的太太 亲爱的
Robert so deserves you my dear.
他在爱情上遭受过不幸
He's been unlucky in love
- 而他的生意... - 嘘
and he's business... Hush,
Mary 记得吗?
Mary, remember?
为什么我就不能把我的话说完?
Why can't I finish what I was going to say?
我们什么时候开饭?
When do we dine?
优雅
Exquisite.
放开我
Get off me.
你给我过来
Come here you.
放开我
Get off me.
-放开我 -不
-Get off me. -No.
这些可怕的事情都是你想像出来的 Oswald
You've merely imagined all these dreadful things Oswald.
都是你的想像
It was your imagination.
这种痛苦对你来说太沉重了
This agony's been too much for you.
-你好 福尔摩斯先生 -我可以进去吗?
-Hello Mr. Holmes. -May I?
当然了 不过里头在彩排...
Yes but there rehearsing...
在家里 跟你的母亲在一起 我亲爱的孩子
At home with your own mother. My blessed boy.
你要什么就有什么
Everything is yours for the asking
就像你小时候一样
just like when you were a little child.
你的发作该结束了
The fit is over now.
母亲 请给我阳光吧
Mother, give me the suns.
Oswald 你到底怎么了?
Oswald what is the matter?
看着我
Look at me.
你不认识我了吗?
Do you not know me?
太阳
The sun.
不
No.
有人在看着我们?
We are being watched?
当着陌生人的面我是不彩排的
I will not rehearse in front of strangers.
走开
Get over there.
Go on your way.
走吧
Come on.
你到底在找什么?
What are you looking for then?
少管闲事
Mind your own business.
不是Robert勋爵送来的
It's not Lord Robert's.
今天可是我们的七周年纪念啊
It's our 7th anniversary isn't it?
七年了
7 years.
这该死的纪念日是你的 不是他的
Your damned anniversary not his.
你知道 他也知道 连猫都知道
You know it, he knows it and the cat knows it.
你到底是怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
出去
Get out.
去 再给我拿瓶酒来 去啊
Go and get me another bottle go on.
我又不是他花钱雇来的婊子
I'm not his whore to be paid off.
他信任我
He trusted me.
我不是你的婊子 我的勋爵大人
I'm not your whore my Lord.
不是的
No.
来吧 来找你的婊子吧 我的勋爵大人
Come and use your whore my Lord.
你永远不会找到一个像我这样
You'll never have anyone
能为你做任何事情的人
who'll do what you want like me.
谢谢
Thank you.
夫人 我要请你原谅
You'll pardon me mam
我不跟你一起喝 那种法国庄园葡萄酒
if I don't join you in drinking that French chateau wine.
对我的口味而言 它太细腻了
I guess it's too refined for my taste.
有些人会说是太高级了
Some would say too civilized.
为您的健康干杯
I'll drink you're health
不过我要喝的是 Samuel Markoolin的黑麦威士忌
but it'll be in Samuel Markoolin's rye.
带有烟味的威士忌
Smoky kind of whiskey.
我到哪儿都会带着它
I travel it with me all over.
真是太明智了 Doran先生
How very wise Mr. Doran.
很明智
Very wise.
要是一个人有了固定的口味 为什么还要...
If one has an established taste why then...
确实如此...确实如此
just say...just say.
这种酒真是太好了 先生
The wine sir is magnificent.
上帝保佑你
Bless you.
你都知道了吧?
You know don't you
我给了Hettie相当可观的一笔钱
I've settled a considerable amount on Hettie
作为她的嫁妆?
for when she's married?
她很清楚您的慷慨 先生
She's very conscious of your generosity sir.
她不止一次地提起过
She's mentioned it more than once.
对
Sure.
现在跟我说说你的这座房子
Now tell me about this house of yours.
是座大房子 可他们告诉我它很阴郁
Great house, sad looking they tell me.
说得不错
I'll accept that
不过我不打算
but I'm not prepared to lay out more
在那里多住
for the time I spend there.
Hettie告诉我房子很美
Hettie has told me how beautiful it is.
我想她愿意把它当成自己的一个家
I think she'd like it to be one of her homes.
我非常愿意尽我所能让Hettie开心
I would want to please Hettie in any way I can
可我觉得住在Glovin是不可能的
but I'm not sure that living in Glovin is possible.
为什么?
Why not?
您一直对我很坦诚
You've always been very frank with me
所以我得向您承认
so I'll admit something to you.
在我更年轻的时候
When I was much younger
那时少不更事
and barely had a grasp of affairs
我得到了一些糟蹋的建议 我是说金钱上
I was very badly advised, financially I mean.
怎么回事?
In what way?
有人说服我卖掉 Glovin的外围部分
I was persuaded to sell off outlying parts of Glovin
结果这处产业就无法 给我带来足够的收入
until there wasn't enough income from the estate
去维持房子的开销
to sustain the house.
接着为了修缮房子我又进行了抵押
Then mortgages were taken out to repair things
这样我的收入就更少了
which left even less income.
没有人警告过你有这样的后果吗?
And nobody warned you of the consequences?
我当时很信任我的顾问
I trusted my advisors.
他们也是我父亲的顾问
They were my father's advisors.
当你在像Glovin那样的地方长大
When you grow up in a place a Glovin
你会觉得那种生活会是永久不变的
it seems eternal.
是的 我明白
Sure I see that?
我要去休息了 Miller小姐
I'll be off then Miss Miller
我希望你也能休息一下
and I hope you'll do the same.
因为你在忙也没意义
Cause there's no point in you doing otherwise.
哦 让我摆脱你这个麻烦的女人吧
Well rid me of this troublesome woman.
-你是我的救世主吗? -我说了 出去
-Are you my savior? -I do say get out.
钻石王老五大婚-- 要问一问为什么吗?
Eminent Bachelor to Marry-Do We Ask Why?
给你 这个可以让你解决问题
Here this should kick things off
在Glovin重新开始
for you to make a start at Glovin.
您真是太慷慨了 先生
How very generous sir.
你照顾我的女儿
You look after my girl.
我就照料你的房子
I'll look after your house.
去Park俱乐部
The Park Club.
Vincent
Vincent.
谢谢
Thank you.
走
Go.
走啊
还记得我们的协议吗 我的勋爵大人
Remember our agreement my Lord.
付四分之一的款项
This quarter's payment
否则我会取消抵押的赎回权
or I will foreclose the mortgages.
今天再过会儿就要结婚了 Callahan
I have to be married later this morning Callahan.
新娘子的父亲是太平洋沿岸最有钱的人
The bride's father is the richest man on the Pacific slope.
她要什么他就会给她什么
Anything she wants he'll give her
只要我能让她开心
as long as I keep her happy.
噢 是啊 好好让她一直开心吧 伙计
Oh yes keep her very happy man.
我的搭档和我无意要占有Glovin
My partner and I have no wish to own Glovin.
请不要逼着我们夺走它
Please don't force us to take it.
剩下的钱会确保那不会发生
Rest assured that you will never come to that.
请原谅 先生们
You'll excuse me gentlemen.
谢谢 Hudson太太
Thank you Mrs. Hudson.
你那表情是在责备我吗?
Is that look of reproach?
不
No.
不 我通常在这个时候起床
No I'm often up at this hour.
这些天我不太睡得着
I don't really sleep these days.
比例
scale
这椅子的比例
The  scale of the chair
上面痕迹的意义
and the sense of the stain of the chair.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝你们万事如意
May all the best to you.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
啊 别碰那该死的东西
Awe, leave the goddamn thing alone.
谢天谢地 您来了 医生
Thank you for coming Doctor.
为什么你不早点叫我来?
Why didn't you call me earlier?
呃 我不想...
Well I didn't what to...
噢 天哪 天哪
oh dear, oh dear.
他当然不肯承认
He won't admit it of course,
可是他病了
but he's not well.
我很担心他
I'm very worried about him.
你该早些告诉我
You should have called me earlier.
可是他不会让我叫你来的
But he wouldn't have it.
你知道他有多专横吧?
Do you know how masterful he is?
我可不敢不听他的
I didn't dare disobey him.
噢 天哪
Oh dear.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
你对梦境有什么认识?
What do you know about dreams?
你问这个干什么?
Why do you ask?
为什么?
Why?
我正穿过阴曹地府 而你还问我为什么?
I'm walking through infernal territory and you ask why?
我不过就是问问
I only meant.
我也不知道我问来干嘛
I don't know what I meant.
呃 在维也纳有一个组织
Well there's a group in Vienna
由一名叫弗洛伊德的年轻医生带领
Iead by a young doctor called Freud,
他是个心理学家 哲学家 精神分析学家
a psychologist,
请别看
Please don't look at them.
它们都是些涂鸦
They are merely scribbles
参考之用
for reference.
他是不是会释梦?
Does he seek to explain dreams?
我想是的 对梦境进行诠释
To interpret them I believe so.
梦与做梦者的生活是有联系的
There relationship to the life a dreamer.
我想他们旨在进行科学的解释
They aim to be scientific I gather.
梦的科学?
The science of dreams,
好吧
well, well, well.
我的梦很可怕
My dream is horrible.
我在瀑布上跟Moriarty搏斗
I'm fighting with Moriarty at the Falls
突如其来的茫然湮没了我
and suddenly I'm overwhelmed with a sense of loss,
恐惧
fear.
是的 恐惧
Yes fear.
空荡荡的房间 我失去了比例感
Empty rooms, I've no sense of scale.
有一张巨大的椅子 然后又变小了
A huge chair, which diminishes.
上面的皮革都被撕成了碎片
It's upholstery torn to shreds.
我开始逃离一片沼泽
I'm starting to escape from a marsh,
一片烂泥 一个泥潭
a mire, a quagmire.
Grimpen沼地
The Grimpen Mire
之后出现了...一只畸形的生物
and it appears than an androgynous creature,
像巫婆 像妖婆
witch like, hag like,
长着爪子 伸向我
with claws, talons, which reach out to me,
穿透我
through me
于是我就困在了....
and I'm trapped...
一张蜘蛛网当中
in a mesh of cobwebs.
然后我就醒了
And I awake.
嗯 你近来吃东西了吗?
Hum, are you eating?
你睡得不好 就做会些噩梦
You sleep badly, you have bad dreams,
就更睡不好了
you sleep even worse.
我没有做很多噩梦
I don't have bad dreams;
我一次又一次地做同一个梦
I have one dream more than once.
那我们来做个检查吧
Well let's see how you really are.
噢 请不要!
Please don't start that.
我还要告诉你一件事
And I'll tell you something else
对于Moriarty的死 我感到很遗憾
I regret Moriarty's death.
说说看 你觉得Moriarty是个什么样的人?
Tell me how would you describe Moriarty?
邪恶的
Evil.
大魔头
A giant of evil.
确实是大魔头 你说得没错
Giant, yes quite so.
没有了他
Without him
我就得跟伤心的小孩 养猫的主人打交道
I have to deal with  distressed children, cat owners,
微不足道
pygmies,
都是些微不足道的琐事!
pygmies of triviality.
你看到了
You see,
Moriarty将科学与邪恶结合了起来
Moriarty combined science with evil.
精确而且有组织
Organization with precision.
充满了想象力与洞察力
Vision with perception.
据我所知 他只错误判断过一个人
I know of only one person that he misjudged.
那就是我
Me.
收起你的药吧
Put away your medicines.
你的研讨会怎么样了?
How was your seminar?
讨论很踊跃
Lively.
那孩子有些不对劲
There's something wrong with the child.
她惴惴不安地像只猫
She is as nervous as a cat.
帽?
Hat?
噢 是的
Oh yes.
Amelia戴着帽子看上去是怪怪的
Amelia does look curious in a hat.
我以前都没这么想过
I never thought of it before.
你当新娘子的那会儿也是很紧张的
Even you were nervous as a bride.
噢 不是那么回事
Oh it's not that,
是有些不对劲
there's something wrong.
我就要宣布开饭了 夫人
I was about to announce my lady.
等我两三分钟 好吗?
Oh give me 2 or 3 minutes would you?
好的 夫人
Very well my lady.
让那女孩子来见我
Get that girl for me.
叫她来
Get her.
叫她来!
Get her!
您的羞怯都上哪儿去了 Miller小姐?
Where is your timidity Miss Miller?
就在你那冰冷的心里 Robert勋爵
In the cold gutter of your heart Lord Robert.
被你践踏在沟渠之中
Trampled in the gutter.
为什么啊?
But why?
我祝你跟那孩子能幸福
I wish the child joy of you.
瞧 Bella 那是著名的Flora Miller
Look Bella there's the famous Flora Miller,
她曾是Robert的一个朋友
she used to be a friend of Robert's
可是我觉得她不再喜欢他了
but I don't think she likes him anymore.
我可以解释
I can explain everything.
那是...呃
It was a
那是很久以前的事情了
it was a long time ago.
你是谁?
Who are you?
她不在楼上
She's not upstairs.
退下
Go away.
房子里头都找过了 上上下下都找遍了
The house has been searched now top to bottom.
连Hettie的影儿都不见
Not a sign of Hettie anywhere.
什么也没有
Nothing.
Alice?
Doran太太的一个斗篷不见了 先生
One of Mrs. Doran's cloaks is missing sir.
没别的了吗?
Nothing else.
没了 先生 连钱包都还在
No sir not even a purse.
谢谢 Alice
Thank you Alice.
我告退了 先生
Sir.
我们应当报警
We must call the police.
你的那个女人呢 那个演戏的
What about this woman of yours, this actress,
跟这事儿会不会有什么关系?
could she have anything to do with it?
我不知道
I don't know.
我去找警察
I'll get the police.
你不反对吧?
Do you have any objection?
不
No.
你在哪儿?
Where are you?
噢 我亲爱的
Oh my darling.
我告诉过你 你该做的事情就是正常吃东西
I've told you what you should be doing is eating properly.
请进
Come in.
来了这个
This has come.
上面写着"十万火急"
It is marked 'Most Urgent.'
Hudson太太  我还不能看
Mrs. Hudson I can still see.
你没事吧 福尔摩斯先生
Are you all right Mr. Holmes.
你知道我多希望我把门锁上了
You know I wish I'd never unlocked the door.
不
No.
上面有私人的亲笔签名
Well it's got a personal autograph.
还算是好的了
That's an improvement.
今天早上的邮件
This morning's mail
是鱼贩和海关监察员来的
was from a fishmonger and a tidewaiter.
哦 还是高级信笺呢
Well that's a fashionable epistle indeed.
我亲爱的歇洛克.福尔摩斯
My dear Sherlock Holmes,
Blackwater勋爵告诉过我
Lord Blackwater tells me
我可以绝对信任
that I may place implicit reliance
您的辨别力与判断力
upon your judgment and discretion.
苏格兰场已经介入此事的调查
Scotland Yard is already acting in this matter
而且对您没有提出任何反对的意见
and there is no objection to you
事情是有关St. Simon勋爵的婚礼
It's about that Lord St. Simon wedding.
是的 没意思 没意思 没意思
Yes dull, dull, dull.
天蓝色 黑色条纹上面有三个蒺藜
Azure, 3 caltrops in chief over a fess sable.
是他 没错
That's him alright.
是St. Simon勋爵 他来早了
It's Lord St. Simon, he's early.
噢 华生 我正要睡觉呢
Watson I'm trying to sleep.
你知道我办案的方法
You know my methods.
让门开着就好
Leave the door open.
福尔摩斯在哪儿啊?
Where is Holmes huh?
福尔摩斯先生身体不适 勋爵
Mr. Holmes is indisposed my Lord.
他委托我进行初步的调查
He has entrusted the preliminaries to me.
我熟悉他的方法
I know his methods.
很好
Very well.
除了这事儿给我造成的悲痛
Apart from the distress this has caused me
你还明白其中的微妙吧?
you understand the delicacy?
完全了解
Indeed.
Blackwater勋爵说
Lord Blackwater said that
福尔摩斯先生以前处理过类似的案件
Mr. Holmes has handled cases of this sort before
尽管我觉得
though hardly I imagine
他们的社会地位与我不可同日而语
from the same class of society.
事实上 他这次算是纡尊降贵了
He would in fact be descending.
先生!
Sir.
福尔摩斯先生处理的上一宗 类似案件的委托人是一位国王
On Mr. Holmes' last client to the sort was a King.
好极了 华生
Very well Watson.
呵 我还不知道呢
Huh, I had no idea.
是哪一位国王呢?
Which King?
呃 勋爵 您应该明白
Well you can understand my Lord
对于其它委托人的事情 他都是完全保密的
that he extends to the affairs of other clients
就像他也会对您的事情三缄其口一样
the same secrecy, which he's promised you in yours.
当然了
Of course.
我们要怎么找到她呢 先生?
How are we to find her sir?
她怎么会失踪呢?
How can she of disappeared?
她在哪儿呢?
Where is she?
我必须把她找回来
I must have her back.
一个藏在暗中的女人
A woman obscured.
就在仪式结束后
It was after the ceremony outside the church
在教堂外头 我开始觉察她有些不对劲
that first noticed that something was wrong.
就在你们出来的时候? 而不是之前?
As you came out and not before?
不是
No.
那她进来的时候呢?
And as she came in?
她显得有些不安
She appeared a little apprehensive
不过看上去还是楚楚动人
but she looked quite lovely
而且很开心
and very happy.
如果我没记错的话
If I remember rightly
报纸上暗示说
the newspapers implied
Miller小姐喝得醉醺醺的
that Miss Miller was drunk
出现在你家门口
when she made the scene at your front door.
据我判断 是的 很有可能她醉了
As far as I could judge yes it was likely.
勋爵 我可以问问
My Lord would it be in order to ask
你和Miller小姐是什么关系吗?
the nature of your relationship with Miss Miller?
可以
Yes.
简单地说 她曾是我的情妇
If somewhat naive she was my mistress.
我们几个月前分手了
We parted some months ago.
我觉得我当时还是很慷慨的
I was I believe generous.
是不是你遇到Doran小姐时候的事?
And that is when you met Miss Doran?
事实上 在那之前
Before in fact.
Miller小姐的酒瘾 之前就曾引起过好几次争吵
Miss Miller's drinking had already led to some scenes.
她渐渐变得不可信任
She was becoming very unreliable.
你是否觉得...
Do you think...
你是否觉得Miller小姐是那种
Do you think Miss Miller's the sort of person
比起让你难堪 更会向你复仇的人?
to seek revenge on you beyond embarrassing you a bit?
酒精对人的影响是难以预料的
Drink affects people unpredictably.
苏格兰场的警察也觉得
But the chap at Scotland Yard also believes
Miller小姐与Hettie的失踪有关
Miss Miller to be implicated in Hettie's disappearance.
你最好还是应应门吧 先生?
Hadn't you better answer the door sir?
什么事?
What?
我知道 我知道 福尔摩斯先生
I know I know Mr. Holmes,
不过事情很奇怪
the circumstances are odd though.
我觉得你该看看这个
I felt you should see this.
两位女士Maud和Helena有何关系?
What of ladies Maud and Helena?
那妇人是位女士
The woman was lady
毫无疑问的
no doubt about it.
她身上有种东西 我觉得
There was something about her,
引人注目
compelling I call it,
非常引人注目
most compelling.
谢谢 Hudson太太
Thank you Mrs. Hudson?
不是她的衣服和面纱
Never mind her clothes and her veil
是她的声音
it was her voice.
她可是位女士
She was a lady.
你是说她戴着面纱?
Did you say she wore a veil?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
Hudson太太 你说得我...脊背发冷
Mrs. Hudson I have a faint, cold fear runs through my veins.
噢 先生
Oh sir.
你把火生起来好吗?
Would you put a match to the fire?
当然好的
Of course.
谢谢 Hudson太太
Thank you Mrs. Hudson.
Robert勋爵
Now Lord Robert.
Maud还有Helena这两个名字
If I were to mention the names Maud and Helena to you
对你来说有什么意义吗?
would they mean anything?
当然了
Certainly they would.
它们是Robert勋爵
They are names of the 2 women
两位前妻的名字
to whom Lord Robert was previously married.
前妻?
Married?
你以前结过婚吗?
You were married?
请原谅我朋友的惊讶 勋爵
Forgive my friend's surprise my Lord.
你干嘛不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
你说你想睡的
You said you wanted to sleep.
我现在清醒得很
Well I'm wide-awake now.
可是你很出名啊
But your known.
都说你是这个国家最让人中意的单身汉
Even celebrated as one of the most eligible bachelors in the country.
我可没想要出名 福尔摩斯先生
I never chose to be celebrated Mr. Holmes.
我一直很满意
I have always been very contented
我的婚姻能躲开公众的视线 福尔摩斯先生
that my marriages be kept from the public gaze Mr. Holmes.
为什么?
Why?
那两次婚姻可不是什么轻松的经历
They were not comfortable experiences.
呵 轻松?
Hum, comfortable?
事实上 很痛苦
Painful indeed.
痛苦?
Painful?
是的 福尔摩斯先生
That is what I said Mr. Holmes.
它们和眼下这件事没有什么关系
They have no bearing on the matter in hand.
那你能不能告诉我 你那两次婚姻是如何结束的呢?
Would you oblige me then by telling me how your marriages ended?
第一次 是我妻子死了
The first, ended in my wife's death.
第二次 被宣告婚姻无效
The second by annulment.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我明白了
I see.
无效的原因呢?
And the grounds of the annulment.
就是被判无效了 福尔摩斯先生
It was annulled Mr. Holmes.
华生 你去把Hudson太太找来好吗?
Watson will you fetch Mrs. Hudson?
Hudson太太?
Mrs. Hudson?
来了
Yeah.
我想让你描述一下送来便条的这位女士
I want you to describe to me the lady who delivered the note.
谢谢
Thank you.
我试试吧
But I'll try sir.
不能只是试试 Hudson太太
No you must do more than try Mrs. Hudson.
你必须说清楚
You must succeed.
呃...她...瞧...瞧 先生
Well...she...Iook...Iook sir,
街道对面 就是她
on the other side of the street that's her.
来啊 华生
Come Watson.
走
Drive on.
停下
Stop.
福尔摩斯
Holmes
该死的!
Damn!
我真拿你没办法
I despair.
是什么?
What is it?
电车票
A tram tickets
还有一本帐本
and an accounts book.
都是些数字
Its just figures.
没有地址
No address.
Hettie女士会步上Maude和Helena的后尘
Lady Hettie gone what of Maude and Helena.
别挡道 Hudson太太
Out of the way Mrs. Hudson.
噢 医生
Oh Doctor.
她是想来暗示什么
[unintelligible]
与失去亲人有关
something about losing a relative.
失去双亲
To lose one's parents
也许就算不幸了
maybe considered unfortunate.
就是这样 那位戴面纱的女士 想暗示的就是这个
That's it. that's what the veiled lady was trying to advise.
失去一位妻子
To lose one wife
可以说是一起不幸
maybe considered unfortunate
可是失去三位妻子呢?
but to lose 3?
看上去是因为他不负责任
Begins to look like carelessness.
已经超过了不负责任  华生
Rank carelessness Watson.
是反常
Freaky.
那位女士究竟是谁?
Who is this woman?
我得读读你那有关Robert勋爵的笔记
I must read your notes on Lord Robert.
噢 讲点道理吧 华生 我会吃东西的
Oh be reasonable Watson I will eat.
你不能离开这个房间 你需要休息
You're not Leaving this room you need rest.
休息?
Rest?
好吧 那你明天早上得去拜会Doran
Well then you'll have to interview Doran tomorrow morning.
没问题
All right.
梦的科学
The science of dreams.
多么神秘的语言啊
What an undiscovered language.
跟我们的先人们想的一样
Like our ancestors thought of them.
梦具有预言性
Prophetic.
行 你看吧
Yes you may look.
具有洞察力
Precognisense.
这个小小的本子
This little book,
我们得等到它干了
we must wait until it dries.
至于那位戴面纱的女士
The woman with the veil
我们必须找到她
she must be found.
很抱歉打扰你 先生
I'm sorry to disturb you sir.
我是Montgomery警官
Inspector Montgomery,
我想看看您是否能辨认一下这个
I wonder if you could identify this.
我想这位年轻的女士
I understand the young lady
在离开屋子的时候
was wearing her wedding dress
是身着婚纱的
when she left the house.
是的 那是Hettie的婚纱
Yes that's Hettie's wedding dress.
很感谢您能拨冗前来
I'm grateful to you for your time.
不客气
Not at all.
大家告诉我拜访福尔摩斯先生
I've been told a visit to Mr. Holmes
是件很愉快的事
is always entertaining if nothing else.
Levington温泉疗养地?
Levington Spa?
Lastrad在Levington温泉疗养地干嘛?
What's Lastrad doing at Levington Spa?
下水啊
Taking the waters.
很遗憾见到你卧病在家 福尔摩斯先生
Oh sorry to see you laid up Mr. Holmes.
肯定给你的调查带来很大的不便
Must cramp your style no end.
不要紧
Never mind.
我们也没闲着
We've not been idle.
我已经拘捕Flora Miller小姐进行询问
I've arrested Miss Flora Miller for questioning.
可Miller小姐将在"伦敦西区"一剧中担任主角啊
But Miss Miller is playing a leading role in the West End.
为什么拘捕她?
Why?
Flora Miller出现在婚礼上
Flora Miller was seen at the wedding.
她来找受害人
Then she came looking for the victim.
还袭击了Robert勋爵
She attacked Lord Robert
离开房子后不久 有人看见 Doran小姐跟她在一起
and then she was seen with Miss Doran shortly after she left her house
可是她什么也不肯说
but she'll tell us nothing about it,
一言不发
nothing.
还有这个东西 福尔摩斯先生
And there's this Mr. Holmes,
此地你知 请速来
You know where to come as soon as you can.
我将等候全天
I will wait all day.
署名是F.M.
And its signed 'F.M.'
给我
-Give it to me.
相当具有决定性的 不是吗?
Fairly conclusive wouldn't you say?
你在哪儿找到的?
Where'd you find this?
就在婚纱的口袋里
In the pocket of the wedding dress.
你看反了
You're looking at the wrong side.
我知道
I know what's on the other side.
对不起 你叫什么?
Excuse me what is your name?
Montgomery
Montgomery.
是位巡官
Inspector.
噢 一位巡官
Oh an inspector.
这纸片是从一张旅馆账单上撕下来的
This is torn from a hotel bill.
房间 8先令 早餐 2先令6便士
Rooms 8 shillings breakfast 2 and 6.
鸡尾酒 1先令 午餐2先令6便士
Cocktails a shilling luncheon 2 and 6
雪利酒一杯 8便士
a glass of sherry, 8 pence.
我看过了 没什么
I have looked at that, there's nothing in it.
据我所知
I know very few hotels
没几家旅馆敢对一杯雪利酒收8便士
that would dare to charge 8 pence for a glass of sherry,
不过 巡官
however inspector
我想见见Miller小姐
I would like to interview please, Miss Miller.
欢迎
You're welcome to her.
再见 福尔摩斯先生
Good day Mr. Holmes,
再见 华生医生
Doctor Watson,
再会
Inspector.
祝您走运
Oh and good luck.
祝你走运
Good luck to you.
一想到Lastrad
The thought of a Lastrad,
在Levington温泉疗养地逍遥自在
Ioose at Levington Spa
我真希望他太太跟他一起去
I do hope his wife went with him.
我需要你那个新潮的烧瓶 还有一小瓶杜松子酒
I need your hip flask and a small bottle of gin.
杜松子酒?
Gin?
那张旅馆账单...
That hotel bill,
这个消息
the message,
应该是通过某种方式
it must have been passed some how
传递给了在教堂里的Doran小姐
to Miss Doran in the church.
问题一  怎么传递的?
Question one, how?
问题二  谁传递的?
Question two, by who?
显然就是那个她跑去会面的人
Clearly by the person she went to meet.
-名字缩写是F.M. -Flora Miller
-With the initials 'F.M.' -Flora Miller.
不一定
I wonder.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
对Miller小姐的证据是越来越不利了
the evidence is looking increasingly good against Miss Miller.
现在我还得到了这位先生的证词
I now have this gentlemen's evidence.
请允许我介绍George Tidy先生
May I introduce Mr. George Tidy?
你好 先生
How do you do sir?
他是Park俱乐部的老门房了
He's the senior porter at the Park Club.
他打算做证说在St.Simon勋爵的婚礼前夜 Miller小姐用一把手枪
He's prepared to testify that Miss Miller took a shot with a pistol
朝勋爵开了一枪
at Lord St. Simon on the night before his wedding.
如果属实的话 那就非常有意思了
If true, its most intriguing.
噢 千真万确的
Oh it's true all right.
千真万确
Tidy先生有证据
Mr. Tidy has the proof.
子弹
The bullet.
啊
There.
是一把小手枪
A pocket gun wouldn't you say
不过不是Miller小姐的
but not Miss Miller's.
不是Miller小姐的?
Not Miss Miller's?
当然不是
No it's certainly not.
能射出会拐弯的子弹的手枪
The gun is yet to be invented
还没发明出来呢 巡官
that can shoot around corners Inspector.
-有人在这儿开了一枪 -这是肯定的
-Well someone took a shot here. -Of course they did
Tidy先生  你觉得开枪的是谁?
now Mr. Tidy who do you think attempted this murder.
我不知道 先生
I've no idea sir.
当时周围还有几个人
But there were several other people about.
但是我注意到 枪响的时候
But I noticed that the door of his Lordship's carriage
勋爵的马车门重重地关上了
banged at the same time as the gun went off.
不过真正引起我注意的
But what really alerted me
是弹射出来的石头碎片
was the chips coming out of the stone.
于是很自然地我就转过身去
Well naturally after that I had to turn
结果发现她站在那里
and there she was,
就是Miller小姐
Miss Miller I mean,
她生气地瞪着我
staring at me furious.
所以你以为是她开了那一枪
As though you thought it was she who had fired the shot?
倒是很自然的事 不过事情不是这样的
Very natural, however it was not.
这事是由一位或几位不知名的人干的
Person or persons unknown.
你它妈是谁?
And who the devil are you?
Miller小姐?
Miss Miller?
我真的知道你不该在这的
I am acutely aware that you should not be here.
很高兴听到你这么说
I'm glad to hear it.
我是歇洛克.福尔摩斯 为您效劳
I'm Sherlock Holmes at your service.
你能为我效劳的 就是去给我弄瓶酒来
Only service you could do me is to be carrying a bottle.
华生
Watson.
好啊 你倒是个蛮有教养的人嘛
Well, well what an extraordinary civilized citizen you turn out to be then.
我是来调查St. Simon夫人失踪一事的
I am here to investigate the disappearance of Lady St. Simon.
那孩子只不过是有了常识
The child simply had the common sense
发现了她把自己送上了什么路
to see what she was letting herself in for.
她把自己送上了什么路呢?
And what was she letting herself in for?
和Robert St. Simon一起生活
A life with Lord Robert St. Simon.
你能说说那样可能的代价吗?
Can you describe what that might entail?
我把所有的事情都告诉那孩子了
I told the child all about it.
我记不太清了
I can't quite remember.
很漫长的一天
It's been a long day.
我累极了
I was very tired.
天知道我告诉了她什么
God knows what I said to her.
我不记得了
I don't remember.
亲爱的福尔摩斯先生
Dear Mr. Holmes,
我 Agnes Northcote
I Agnes Northcote,
神志清醒 身体健康...
being of sound mind and body...
你注意到Hettie Doran小姐离开了房子
You observed Miss Hettie Doran leave the house,
你向她做了自我介绍
you introduced yourself to her.
你们一起在公园散步
You walked together in the park.
你告诉她要提防St. Simon勋爵
You warned her against Lord St. Simon.
没错
Yes.
她有没有试图捍卫Simon勋爵?
Did she try to defend Sir Simon to you?
没有
No.
一点也没有吗?
Not at all?
她就说了句"谢谢你"
All she said was thank you
"这事让我下定了决心"
that has decided me.
噢 继续说吧
Oh, go on.
你把她带回了剧院
You took her back to the theatre
又派人去买了些衣服 是吧?
and sent out for some clothes?
是的
Yes.
她身上带了钱吗?
Had she money with her?
没有 衣服的钱是我付的
No, I bought the clothes
我还给了她几个金币
and I gave her a couple of sovereign.
你真是太好心了
That was very good of you.
哪里
Not at all.
她说她父亲会偿还这笔钱的
She told me her father would reimburse it all.
她还替我写了张便条给他
She wrote a note to him for me.
啊 一张便条
Ah a note.
你能谈谈St. Simon勋爵之前的几次婚姻吗?
Now can you tell me anything about Lord St. Simon's previous marriages?
没什么
Nothing.
没什么?
Nothing?
是没什么 我就为现在而活
Nothing. I live for the present
其它的事情都是浪费时间
and nothing else is a waste of time.
你对他第一任妻子的死一无所知吗?
You know nothing about his first wife's death?
是的
Nothing.
第二次婚姻被宣布无效
The second marriage was annulled,
你知道为什么吗?
do you know why?
不知道
No.
通常只有当夫妻双方 有一方不适合结婚时
Well an annulment usually takes place
婚姻才会被宣布无效
when there's unfitness in one of the partners.
你知道是怎么回事吗?
Do you know what that might be?
不知道
No.
不知道?
No?
一无所知吗?
Nothing?
是不是他什么都不许你谈?
You're not permitted to discuss anything?
不是的
No.
我可以问问为什么吗?
May I ask why?
不行
No.
根本没有哪个男人
Not any a man
能配得上这样的爱
should be worthy of such love.
是不是因为激情?
Is it passion?
还是恐惧?
Fear?
噢 我明白了 Miller小姐
Oh I see Miss Miller
是兼而有之
it's both.
我告诉你
I apprise you I shall do my best
我会尽力确保你
to see that you are released
摆脱这种毫无道理的羁押
from this nonsensible confinement.
Miller小姐
Miss Miller?
我要做
I'll do it.
差不多好了
It is nearly ready
你知道Doran女儿失踪一案
You know the disappearance of Doran's daughter
应该是很简单的
ought to be a simple matter.
无须什么协助 谜底会自动揭开
It should solve itself without further assistance.
可是Robert勋爵呢?
But what about Lord Robert?
他干了什么会招来三个复仇天使
What has he done to warrant 3 avenging angels,
或是女巫?
witches?
女巫?
Witches?
呃 躲在黑暗里的一个女人
Well a woman obscured.
也许时间的进程被调整过了
Perhaps time is shaped.
我们无法梦到未来
We cannot dream the future.
噢 也许未来就在我们身边 我准备好了
Oh maybe the future is all around us, I'm ready.
就来
Coming.
很遗憾里头的线索如此之少
It's a pity there's so little in this.
只有一些数字和缩写字母
Just a few figures and initials.
毫无疑问 你会有更多发现的
No doubt you'll find more.
噢 你看
Oh look.
好像是蝴蝶脆弱的翅膀
It's like a delicate membranes of a butterfly.
噢 这可怜的女人真是一贫如洗
Oh the poor woman is destitute.
赤贫
Destitute.
书页间充满了愤怒
Ah their's rage on this page.
看看她是怎么撕掉这些纸的
Look how she's torn the paper.
噢 这是什么?
Oh what have we here?
一根线
A thread.
是一位女裁缝吗?
A seamstress?
还是一个做花边的?
Lace maker?
或是一个编织工?
Web maker?
哈 她还爱读书
Ah she reads.
Bronte  Jane Austen 和Sophocles (均为著名作家)
Bronte, Jane Austen and Sophocles.
请进
Coming.
戴面纱的女士 她回来了
The woman with the veil, she's back.
歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
是的 正是在下
Yes I am he.
我们以前见过
We've met before.
我是Agnes Northcote
I am Agnes Northcote.
Northcote小姐
Miss Northcote.
您有什么要告诉我的吗?
What have you to say to me?
在我告诉您这个之前
Before I can tell you that
我必须先知道 您和St. Simon勋爵有什么关系
I must know your connection with Lord St. Simon.
什么关系也没有
None.
华生
Watson?
我们在调查他妻子失踪一案
We are investigating his wife's disappearance.
噢 你不该找她
Oh you must not find her.
你这样说得有理由才行
Such an edict requires justification.
任何有钱的女人 都逃脱不了他的毒手 相信我
No woman with a fortune is safe from him believe me.
-相信我 -是嘛?
-Believe me. -Really?
可是我的思维
Well I'm afraid I am burdened
是很理性的
with a rational turn of mind,
我需要证据
I need proofs.
Northcote小姐 我需要证据
Miss Northcote I need proofs.
我没有证据
I have no proof
但是我坚信如此
only my conviction
而且还曾经经历过 不只是我的经历
and experiences not just my own.
坚信 那可是难得的东西
Conviction well that's a luxury
我差点都忘了
that I have almost forgotten.
显然你有很多要告诉我们的 Northcote小姐
You clearly have much to tell us Miss Northcote
请坐 请坐下
please, please sit down.
我要说的是关于我姐姐的事
I have about my sister.
我能说说她发生了什么事吗?
Shall I tell you what happened to her?
那就是我来这儿的原因
That is why I came.
Helena是我见过的人当中
Helena was more alive
最有活力的
than anyone I've ever met.
她有她自己的财产
She had her fortune
她的命运掌握在她自己手中 这可是很多女人难得拥有的
she was in charge of her fate, as few women are,
直到她遇见了Robert St. Simon勋爵
until she met Lord Robert St. Simon.
他毁了她
He destroyed her.
他夺去了她的财产
He took her fortune,
他娶了她
he married her
又把她毁了
and he destroyed her.
怎么回事?
How?
他让人把她送到一家精神病院里头
He had her committed to a mad house.
只需要两个医生的签名
It required only the signature of 2 doctors
这事就办成了
and the deed was done.
那是什么时候的事?
When was this?
现在这样的事情不可能发生的
It could not happen today,
我们有
we have the Lunacy Act.
噢 不可能吗?
Oh could it not?
呃 也许是吧
Well that's as maybe
可是条例的出台对我姐姐来说太迟了
but the act came too late for my sister
当条例实施的时候
and when the Lunacy Act became enforced
他还是让人把她关进了精神病院
he still had her put away.
我们不能随便把人关进精神病院的
People can't just be put away.
当然可以 如果你的叔叔是位公爵就行
They can if you're uncle is a Duke.
要是你长得英俊又能花言巧语也行
If you're handsome and plausible
而且是基于你刚才说的条例
under the terms of your precious act
我要求他们对她被关押的情况
I demanded that conditions of her confinement
...作出评估  他们也做了
were inspected and so they were.
一个小小的学术委员会最终到了Glovin
A small but learned committee went to Glovin eventually.
Helen
Helen.
他们知道他们得找什么
Knowing what they wanted to find
当然他们就找到了
and of course they found it.
他们被富有同情心的Robert勋爵迷惑了
Charmed by the compassionate Lord Robert
他把她的妻子关起来 是因为他曾经貌美如花的妻子
who had kept his wife a profoundly depressed person.
极度情绪低落 而且令人伤心地迷失了自我
Once beautiful now sadly destructed
而他的妻子受到了令人赞叹的照顾 环境干净
in conditions that can only be wondered at for their cleanliness,
整洁
they're orderliness,
看护质量很高等等
their quality of nursing and so on.
只有一件事情他们没有注意到
Only one thing was amiss,
那就是那个人不是我姐姐
it was not my sister.
Helena并没有疯
Helena was not mad.
那人不是她
It was not her.
他雇了别人来冒充她
He'd hired someone.
Flora Miller
Flora Miller.
Robert!
那不是我姐姐
It was not my sister.
不是她
It was not her.
那她现在在哪儿?
And where is she now?
我自己去了一趟Glovin
I went to Glovin myself.
我得查清真相
I had to find the truth.
我的收获就是这个
My reward was this.
Northcote小姐?
Miss Northcote?
你发现真相了吗?
Did you discover the truth?
没有
No.
我不知道该怎么做
I did not know how to.
我被愤怒和悲伤蒙蔽了
I was blind with anger and grief.
我甚至想不起我是怎么到那儿去的
I have no recollection of even how I got there.
我只知道有一天我发现我自己
I only know that I found myself one day
正穿过那个该死的地方 一重重的门
walking through the gates of that accursed place.
我被扔在树林之中
I was left in part of the wood
那是关动物的地方
where the animals are kept
那样事情看上去
so it might look as though
就像是我没有听从劝告去了那里
I had been attacked by one of them
而受到了一头动物的袭击
after ignoring notices not to.
我被一些佃农发现了
I was found by some cottagers.
才活了下来
And kept alive.
要是您能查出我姐姐是死是活 我将万分感激
I would thank you to find out whether my sister was alive or not.
不查清楚这事
I only live a half-life
我虽生犹死
for not knowing.
没有什么能驱除我心里的阴霾
Nothing seems to break the gray cycle I live in.
不管我做什么
Nothing I do.
什么都不行
Nothing.
夜晚我穿过街道
I walk the streets at night,
寻找着危险
Iooking for danger.
有时我觉得我是在 请求这个世界给予我伤害
Sometimes I think I'm asking the world to hurt me
好让我觉得我还活着
so I can feel alive.
天哪 我梦见的就是这个啊
Good God what else may I've dreamt?
送洗的衣服?
The laundry?
Northcote小姐 您能再告诉我一件事吗?
Miss Northcote will you satisfy me upon one point?
我愿尽我所能
If I can.
你在流浪
You're meanderings,
在夜里流浪
nocturnal meanderings,
有没有走过Park俱乐部?
do they ever take you past the Park Club?
St. Simon勋爵 在婚礼前夜遭到枪击
Lord St. Simon was shot at on the night before his wedding
是你干的吧?
that was you?
我无法眼睁睁地看着 另一条生命遭到毁灭
Couldn't bear to see another life destroyed.
Robert勋爵的妻子
Lord Robert's wife,
他的第一任妻子是被谋杀的
first wife, was murdered.
谋杀?
Murdered?
她也拥有一笔财产
She also had a fortune.
他们在法国度完蜜月不久
She was robbed and killed
她就遭到了抢劫并被杀害了
shortly after their honeymoon in France.
谁干的?
By who?
一个叫Thomas Floutier的人
A man called Thomas Floutier.
他被定罪了吗?
Was he convicted?
是的 可是他逃走了
Yes but he escaped
他现在在哪儿?
and where is he now?
你觉得他在哪儿?
Where do you think he is?
知道吗?
Any idea?
Glovin
Glovin.
不 我不知道...不知道
No I don't know... I don't know.
我没有证据
I have no proof.
只不过是凭借直觉吧
Just the strength of your convictions.
是的
Yes.
Northcote小姐
Miss Northcote
恐怕你那一枪的声音
I'm afraid the sound of your shot
没有传到我们高贵的单身汉的耳朵里啊
never reached the ears of our noble bachelor.
第三次结婚的St. Simon勋爵
The thrice married Lord St. Simon.
我不能指望你明白
I cannot expect you to understand
我有多羡慕你
how much I envy you.
棋逢对手
A delight it must be
真是令人愉快
to face an opponent of some worth.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
Hudson太太?
Mrs. Hudson?
他真的会帮忙吗?
Is he really going to help?
噢 当然了
Oh yes.
他已经在帮忙了
He already is.
Bella当时在教堂里
Bella was in the church.
对吧 我的宝贝
Weren't we my sweetness,
我悄悄把Bella带了进去
I smuggled Bella in.
她像金子般闪耀
She was as good as gold.
发生了什么事吗?
Did anything occur?
噢 没有什么异常的
Oh nothing occurred out of the ordinary.
我向你保证
I'll assure you.
好好想想
Please try to remember.
哦对了 甜蜜的小Hettie 把花束掉在地上了
Oh yes, sweet little Hettie dropped her bouquet you know.
有人把它捡了起来
And had it picked up for her.
-掉了花束 -那人挺迷人的
-Dropped her bouquet. -He was quite an attractive,
我是说那个帮她捡起花束的人
the one who picked it up I mean.
我想大概是Doran家的一个亲戚
One of the Doran's I suppose.
他看上去一身美国味
He looked American at any rate.
谢谢
Thank you.
Duarte
Duarte.
你不会碰巧还有一个女继承人备用吧?
You don't I suppose have another heiress up your sleeve?
见你的鬼 Callahan
Damn you Callahan.
你都看到了
The newspapers you see
报纸上报道了你岳父家门口发生的
reported a scene of disgusting vulgarity
恶心粗鄙的一幕
on your father in-law's doorstep.
我纳闷你要怎么对他解释?
I wonder how you'll explain that to him?
Doran觉得我清白无辜
Doran doesn't think me uninnocent.
他接受了我的故事
He accepted my story.
显而易见 Miller小姐喝醉了
It was clear to everyone that Miss Miller was drunk.
而你则从我的搭档那里
And managed to obtain from my partners
获得了一次缓刑
a temporary stay of execution.
就这样了
That's all
一天还是两天?
a day or two?
你必须给我证据
You must have proof.
证明什么 看在老天的份上?
Proof of what for God's sake?
证明那只加州的小鹅
Proof that the Californian goose
还愿意把金蛋下在Glovin 就这样
remains willing to lay its golden eggs at Glovin that's all.
-这事不会搞砸了吧? -没有
-Nothing was jeopardized that? -No
-没有? -没有 当然没有
-Nothing? -No of course not.
那Miller小姐呢?
What about Miss Miller?
要是她能唱那么一出戏
If she's capable of a scene like that.
她还能唱别的什么吧?
What else is she capable of?
我希望她没有什么别的事情可说了
I hope she has nothing else to reveal.
相信我
Trust me.
一点也不 勋爵
Not an inch my Lord.
我刚刚发现一位 叫Francis Hay Moulton的先生
I just discovered a Mr. Francis Hay Moulton
住在26号房间
is in room 26.
一位美国绅士
An American gentleman
他的妻子昨天刚刚才到
whose wife only joined him yesterday.
他名字的缩写是F.H.M.
His initials are F.H.M.,
F.M.
- 啊 对不起 - 等等 先生
-Ah excuse me, -One moment please sir.
有什么能为您效劳的吗?
And how can I assist you sir?
雪利酒一杯多少钱?
How much is a glass of sherry?
8便士
That would be 8.
谢谢
Thank you.
我私底下答应了Moulton先生
I personally promise Mr. Moulton
说你们两个都可以自由地回加州去
that you will both be free to return to California.
就当是 你的妻子从未进过那家教堂
It will be as if you're wife had never entered that church.
你是怎么找到我们的?
How did you find us?
这个并不重要
That is unimportant.
要是你想听听我的看法
If I may give you my opinion
我想这里头的秘密太多了一点
I think there's been a little too much secrecy already.
我可以跟Moulton太太谈谈吗?
May I speak to Mrs. Moulton?
你要先告诉我你们两个到底是谁才行
Not before you tell who the devil you are.
我们受雇于St. Simon勋爵 他要我们寻找他的妻子
We're been engaged by Lord St. Simonto find his wife.
Moulton先生 她父亲的反应会很激烈的
Mr. Moulton, her father will take it very hard
我想她没有跟他沟通过
I think that she did not communicate with him.
可是她有的 该死的 她有沟通过
But she did damn it, she did.
没错 Flora Miller的便条
And yes the note from Flora Miller
现在应该到他手上了
he would have received it by now.
很好
Good.
她父亲从未认可我
Her father never approved of me.
噢 是嘛
Oh really.
你知道在Gulf Shores... (在阿拉巴马州)
You see up in the Gulf Shores...
当然这就是她父亲的理由了
Surely these are explanations for her father.
要是你能听我说完
You made criticism of Henrietta's duties
你会发现你是在批评Henrietta 对她父亲的孝心了
towards her father if you'll hear me out.
我答应了老Doran
I promised old man Doran
我会离开 不再打扰Henrietta
I'd go away and not trouble Henrietta
直到我出人头地
until I'd made my way
不过我们在我离开之前秘密结了婚
but we got married in secret before I went.
后来 有人告诉他们 我死在西北了
Then I was reported dead up in the high northwest
Henrietta于是 就把我们秘密结婚的事告诉他了
so Henrietta told him then about our secret marriage.
他派人去调查 看我是否像他们说的那样死了
He sent someone out to check I was dead like they said.
那人一直没有找到我
That man never found me
Henrietta因我的死而死心了
so Henrietta gave me up for dead.
Francis Harry Moulton先生
And so Mr. Francis Harry Moulton
大概你是出人头地了吧
presumably you have made your way.
我现在经营旅馆 先生
I'm in hotels sir.
旅馆?
Hotels?
真的吗?
Really?
真的
一杯雪利酒你收费多少?
How much do you charge for a glass of sherry?
跟这家旅馆一样 8便士
The same as this hotel, 8 pence.
Robert?
Flora?
我亲爱的
My darling.
太迟了 Robert
It's too late Robert.
我把所有的事情都告诉那孩子了
I told the child everything.
不管怎么说St. Simon勋爵本来可以 省下雇佣你们的钱的
Anyway Lord St. Simon may as well of saved his money from employing you.
你说这话什么意思?
Why do you say that?
因为Henrietta去见他了
Because Henrietta has gone to see him.
我真希望她不要那么做
I wish she had not done that.
Flora Miller谢世
FLORA MILLER DEAD
你好 Hettie 我亲爱的
Hello Hettie my darling.
你上哪儿去了?
Where have you been?
去哪儿了?
Where you'd disappear to?
她在哪?
Where is she?
你妻子在哪?
Where is your wife?
你就是我的妻子
You're my wife.
我都不知道我算什么
I don't know what I am anymore.
你说什么啊?
What are you saying?
Robert 你干嘛不告诉我?
Robert why didn't you tell me?
告诉你什么?
Tell you what?
所有的一切
Everything.
一切有关你妻子们的事情
Everything about your wives.
那都是过去的事了
It's the past.
无关紧要
Unimportant.
我不想再旧事重提
I don't want to relive the past.
过去已经死去
the past is dead.
而你 你才是未来
You, you are the future.
-她在哪儿? -谁?
-Where is she? -Who?
你的妻子
Your wife.
我只有你
I have only you.
亲爱的 我的那段婚姻已经无效了
My darling the marriage was annulled.
你跟Flora Miller谈过吗?
Have you been talking to Flora Miller?
我知道你准谈过
I know you have.
噢 亲爱的 我求你别听那女人的
Oh my darling I beg you not to listen to that woman.
她是个醉鬼
She is a drunk
她毫无廉耻 满口谎言
she has no sense of decency or truth left.
Helena现在在哪?
Where is Lady Helena now?
我怎么知道?
How should I know?
她正受到照料
Being cared for.
你关心她吗 Robert?
Do you care for her Robert?
我花钱请人照看她
I pay for her care.
看见她太让人痛苦了
Seeing her is to painful.
那可怜的人自我虐待 受尽折磨 满脑子幻觉
The poor creature is afflicted with self-persecution and instilled with delusions
每次我去...
every time I have been...
当局已经要求我不要再去了
the authorities have asked me not to go anymore.
当局?
The authorities?
她还活着吗 Robert?
Is she alive Robert?
你说什么啊?
What are you saying?
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我相信Flora Miller
I believe Flora Miller.
我相信她对我说的话
I believe what she told me
想想都让我觉得恶心
and it makes me ill to think it.
我还以为她是个醉鬼
And I thought she was a drunk
只不过是又一个醉鬼 但那又怎样
just another drunk but it didn't mean anything.
你从一家私人医院带走了Helena
You took Lady Helena away from a private hospital,
你带走了她 她在哪 Robert?
you took her away, where is she Robert?
-这样做对你没有好处 -你把她带到这儿来了
-This is no good. -And brought her here.
-她在哪儿? -这样做对你没好处 该死的!
-Where is she? -It's no good damn it!
噢 上帝啊 这有什么要紧吗?
Oh God, what does it matter?
杀害你第一任妻子的凶手 为什么逃走了 Robert?
Why did the murderer of your first wife escape Robert?
那凶手为什么逃走了?
Why did the murderer of your first wife escape?
逃到哪里去了?
Where to?
你在这儿是不是有个仆人 Robert?
Do you have a servant here Robert?
他是不是叫Thomas Floutier?
Is his name Thomas Floutier?
住口!
Quit!
你以为你能干什么?
What do you think you could do?
看在上帝的份上
For God's sake.
当我...当我让你走
When...when I let you go.
Hettie  Hettie 我做的一切都是为了你
Hettie, Hettie what I did I did for you.
有了你 世界都改变了
With you the world changed.
Hettie  Hettie 你一定要相信我
Hettie, Hettie you must believe me,
说你相信我
say you believe me.
绝不
Never.
死也不说
Not this side of hell.
很好
Very well.
够了
That's it.
都结束了
It's over.
没错
Yes.
在这儿替我干活的 是Floutier没错
It's Floutier the man who works for me here.
除了别的事
Amongst other things
他还照料Helena
he looks after the needs of Lady Helena.
你的固执
It may give you some satisfaction to know
将会让她送命的
that your stubbornness will be
这下你满意了吧?
the inevitable cause of her death now.
当然还有你的命
Yours too of course.
Floutier将会替你安排一起事故
Floutier will arrange an accident for you.
你的钱都会是我的了
Money will revert to me.
适当地哀悼上一阵子
And after a suitable period of morning
我就会离开
I'll leave.
你以为我爸爸
And you think Pa would
会就这么让你带着我的钱离开吗?
Iet you just walk off with my money?
法律是不容争议的
You can't argue with the law.
你是我的妻子
You're my wife.
不
No.
不是的
I'm not.
你觉得在教堂里 我出了什么事呢 Robert?
What do you think happened to me in the church Robert?
我把花束掉在地上了
When I dropped my bouquet.
那是因为我当时看见了我的丈夫
I saw the man I married.
一个鬼魂
A ghost.
我以为他死了
I thought he was dead.
知道我去了哪儿吗
But that's where I've been.
我和我的丈夫在一起
With my husband.
不!
No!
空荡荡的房间
Empty rooms.
还有那气味
The scent.
Thomas Floutier
Thomas Floutier.
华生 照顾她
Watson take care of her.
我经过了怎样的等待啊
How I've waited.
我在黑暗里 哭啊哭啊 就为这一刻
How I've cried again and again in the darkness for this moment.
我知道
I know.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你妹妹Agnes派来的
Emissaries of your sister Agnes.
告诉我
Tell me
你是怎么做到的?
how did you do it?
我花了漫长的7年
I spent 7 long years
把这小教堂搞得摇摇欲坠
insuring the chapel's utter instability.
我试过逃跑 但没有一次成功
Any attempt I made to escape was thwarted
于是我改建了这个入口
so I recreated the entrance
一砖块一块砖
brick by brick,
一根木头一根木头
timber by timber.
我科学地利用了结构的不稳定性
I made a science of instability
我成功了
and I succeeded.
7年了
7 years.
在我的办案中 这是独一无二的
It was unique in my experience
先伏法 后犯罪
to serve a sentence before committing the crime.
护士?
Nurse?
我们就是这样发现了 Glovin真正的女主人
And so it was that we discovered the true Mistress of Glovin.
一个毫不疯癫
A woman so far from madness
因而得以幸存于如此...不...
who had survived so...no...
她如此成功地
who had so triumphantly,
在7年的禁锢后幸存下来
triumphantly survived 7 years of captivity
以至于福尔摩斯很乐意把她
that Holmes was pleased to call her
称之为他所见到过的
one of the finest minds
最聪明的人
he had ever encountered.
遇到了她
In meeting her
我想福尔摩斯也就揭开了 他那些梦的谜团
I believe Holmes solved the riddle of his dreams.
现在唯一让他困扰的是
It only troubles him now
他无法否认 可能梦也具有预言性
in so far as he cannot deny the possibility that it was prophetic.
Glovin的新主人并非别人
The new owner of Glovin
而正是Helena St. Simon女士
was none other than Lady Helena St. Simon.
Helena女士明智地决定要把它卖掉
Lady Helena wisely decided to sell it
并且赎回用它作抵押的东西
and redeem the mortgages upon it.
正因为有了Moulton一家
I cannot conceive of a happier prospect
还有他们家庭的幸福未来
than to imagine Glovin restored
使得Glovin恢复了生机
for the enjoyment of the Moulton's
我无法想象比这更好的前景了
and their future family.
你竟敢...
How dare you.
你竟敢记录这件案子
How dare you make a record of this case.
记录...不不不
Rec...no, no, no, no.
我只不过是在回复
I'm merely answering an invitation
另一个研讨会的请柬罢了
to another seminar.
真的吗?
Really?
那快点 我们一小时后要动身了
Well be quick, we leave in an hour.
干嘛去?
What for?
看在上帝的份上 当然是看演出了
For heavens sake what's in the performance?
谢谢
Thank you.